hersheys.com 2008-12-17

# Privacy Policy - HERSHEY'S

Welcome to The Hershey Company Internet web sites!   
We are proud to have this opportunity to tell you a little about our company, our products and our history. Along the way, we also hope you have some fun. Before you begin exploring, we'd like to review the steps we have taken to ensure that on-line visitors of all ages have a safe, enjoyable experience. 

Your privacy is important to us. At **** The Hershey Company, we value our consumer's privacy and have made it our policy to provide on-line content that requires minimal collection of information from our visitors. Furthermore, to better protect your privacy we provide this notice explaining our on-line information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. To make this notice easy to find, we make it available on our homepage and at every point where personally identifiable information may be requested. Any significant changes to this Privacy Policy shall be printed in blue italics for a period of 30 days. 

We take seriously our responsibility to our many young consumers. Our sites have been designed 

_primarily for our adult consumers to enjoy, but they also have been designed to be_ ~~ _to be fun_~~ accessible, safe for kids of all ages, and to adhere to all applicable laws and regulations. Children under the age of 13 and their parents should review the section of this policy called "A Word to Parents About Kids’ Privacy" which discusses the special steps we take for young children who may visit our pages. 

Below are some of the ways in which a visitor may provide information to us on-line and how we may use that information. 

Our web servers automatically recognizes a visitor's domain name, however, they do not recognize a visitor's e-mail. 

Cookies and web beacons __ are small bits of information that a web site transfers to an individual's computer for record keeping purposes. We use cookies in a variety of ways to create a more personalized on-line experience for the user. For example, cookies may be used to enhance your experience with games, to reduce the number of repeat questions provided, to ensure that a promotion is not entered more than the permitted number of times, to create a recipe box, or to monitor how effective our ads on third party sites are at bringing visitors to our web pages. The Hershey’s Gifts web site located at _[HersheyGifts.com](http://www.hersheygifts.com/HDG_Home.aspx)_ and Mauna Loa web site at _[MaunaLoa.com](http://www.maunaloa.com/)_ , use cookies to keep track of your shopping bag. These cookies contain no personal information about you and no one but Hershey’s Gifts or Mauna Loa can retrieve the cookies. We use a cookie in the Hershey’s Kitchens area when you build a recipe box. This cookie is the key to your recipe box and is stored within your browser. The purpose for this cookie is to allow the system to recognize you as a return visitor and populate your recipe box with the recipes you have added. On our Investor Relations web site, a cookie is used for user profile verification. Personally identifiable information which may be obtained through cookies or web beacons is not sold, rented or provided to third parties and is not used internally by The Hershey Company for any purpose other than to enhance your experience on our web site. 

We do not require visitors to register or provide any information before entering our web sites. However, there are several places where visitors may choose to provide personally identifiable information about themselves or other people. Unless we tell you otherwise, Hershey will use the information for the purpose the information was provided.

For example:

  * **Questions** : On some pages our visitors can submit comments or ask questions. The only personally identifiable information that we collect is the sender’s e-mail address. We do not save any personally identifiable information associated with comments, and we only save e-mail addresses associated with questions in order to respond to those questions. 

  * **E-Cards** : Visitors to some of our pages can send electronic cards by providing the name and  e-mail address for the sender and recipient. The information provided cannot be viewed by Hershey. The information is used only to allow the sender and recipient to view the e-card and is then automatically deleted. 

  * **Promotions & Sweepstakes**: We frequently offer __ promotions and sweepstakes on our pages. In order to enter a promotion and/or sweepstake or to access certain web site content, we might require you to register online. All visitors under the age of 13 must gain permission from a parent or guardian prior to completing their online registration. During the registration process, we collect information necessary for prize fulfillment and will not share this information with any third party companies unless it is for prize fulfillment purposes. ~~_If a prize is valued at over $600, a social security number will be requested._~~ _If you win a prize, additional information may be collected offline for tax and prize fulfillment purposes._ Your online registration may be used across our web sites to enter multiple promotions and/or sweepstakes or to access certain content. The first initial, last name, hometown and state of all winners will be included on a Winners List. The Winners List will be provided upon request and as required by law. Information required for tax purposes, the Winner’s List or other information required by law is kept as required by law. We also may use the email address that you provide to send you promotional offers if you opt in. 

  * **Coupons** : Sometimes we offer coupons by mail to web visitors who provide us with their name and mailing address ~~_when there is an offer available online._~~ ~~_The information provided is used only to mail the coupons and is deleted within 60 days of the mailing of the coupons._~~ _  The information provided may also be used to facilitate that same visitor's entry into a sweepstakes or contest so that the consumer does not have to repeatedly enter the same information._

  * **Tell-a-Friend** : We may give you the ability to tell your friends about features on our websites. In order to use this Tell-A-Friend feature, we ask you to provide your friends’ first names and e-mail addresses. We also ask that you provide your first name and e-mail address. The name and e-mail address of your friend is used only to send the notification to your friend. We do not keep your friends’ e-mail addresses or use them for any other purposes. We do not keep your e-mail address or use it for any other purposes. If your friends have “opted out” of communications from our company's e-mail at least 72 hours or more before your send-a-friend email, they will not receive a notification through the Tell-A-Friend feature.

  * **E-mail Newsletters** : If you are over the age of 13, some of our pages permit you to register to receive e-mail newsletters or updates in the future by providing your e-mail address. Any e-mail you receive from Hershey will allow you to change your preference or "unsubscribe" from this informational service at any time. At the bottom of each promotional email, there is a link stating "Click here to change or remove your subscription". Clicking that link will lead to a page where you can immediately remove your subscription.

  * **Hershey’s Gifts and Mauna Loa Catalog:** Information is collected when you visit Hershey's Gift Catalog on-line at _[HersheyGifts.com](http://www.hersheygifts.com/HDG_Home.aspx?X=1)_ or the Mauna Loa Gift Catalog at _[MaunaLoa.com](http://www.maunaloa.com/)_ __ and choose to make a purchase or register with our membership service. This information is required to process and confirm your order and is retained to provide you with the ability to maintain an on-line mailing list and to track past gift selections. On occasion we make our Hershey’s Gifts and Mauna Loa customer list of names and mailing addresses (but not e-mail addresses or phone numbers) available to carefully screened companies with products we think may be of interest to our customers. Most of our customers enjoy receiving such material. If you prefer not to, please call the HERSHEY'S GIFTS Customer Service Department at 1-800-454-7737. From September through December a HERSHEY'S GIFTS Specialist is available 24 hours a day, 7 days a week except for Christmas Day. From January through August the daily hours are 7:00 AM Eastern through midnight. Our Membership Service also allows you to choose to receive e-mails from us reminding you of special occasions. In addition, if you have made a purchase or registered with our Membership Service, we may contact you via e-mail to determine if you are interested in receiving newsletters and selected information about Hershey’s products via e-mail in the future. If you specifically agree to receive these contacts, we will send you newsletters from time to time. Any e-mail you receive from us will allow you to change your preference or "unsubscribe" from this informational service at any time. At the bottom of each promotional email, there is a link stating "Click here to change or remove your subscription". Clicking that link will lead to a page where you can immediately remove your subscription. Visitors may also e-mail our Gift Catalog’s customer service representatives with questions at any time. When you use this service, we retain your e-mail address only in order to respond to your questions. You must be 18 or older to purchase products from our on-line catalog. 

  * **Job Applications:** We will use the information submitted in on-line job applications for the sole purpose of filling the specific position applied for by the applicant. After this position is filled, we will retain the information submitted for the period of time required by applicable law. During this retention period, the application will be considered inactive, and the applicant will be considered for other positions only if he/she submits an additional application for those specific positions. We will not release information submitted in on-line job applications to third parties except to appropriate governmental authorities when such release is required by law. 

  * **Auctions:** Visitors to some of our web sites can participate in on-line auctions. We only collect information which is required for participation in the auction and delivery of merchandise to auction winners. All personally identifiable information submitted is used for the purpose of the auction. _The same information may also be used to facilitate that same visitor's entry into a sweepstakes or contest so that the consumer does not have to repeatedly enter the same information._

  * **Other Features:** There may be other features available on our web sites which may require some personally identifiable information to use the feature. We only use the personally identifiable information to provide the feature _ ~~and delete it within a reasonable period of time after the information is no longer necessary.~~_

Business Partners

We have some business partners with whom we may operate some of our pages and share information. For example, on occasion we may offer a sweepstakes jointly with another company. In such instances, information may be shared with the co-sponsor so that the sweepstakes may be conducted. Another situation in which information may be shared is when we have licensed our trademarks to another company to manufacture or distribute a particular product. ~~HERSHEY’S MILK, for example, is distributed by Morningstar Foods, a subsidiary of Dean Foods. Accordingly, information received by the HERSHEY’S MILK web site is shared by Hershey, Morningstar Foods and Dean Foods. Dean Foods can be contacted at [**webmaster@deanfoods.com**](mailto:webmaster@deanfoods.com). Morningstar Foods can be contacted at  [**webmaster@suiza.com**](mailto:webmaster@suiza.com)~~.

Aggregate Information

Aggregate information about which pages visitors access or visit (for example, to enter a visitor in a contest or to send the visitor information) is only used for internal review as we continue to improve our web site. __ Non-personally identifiable aggregate information is shared with third parties. If you prefer not to allow us to collect this information, you can do so by turning off the cookies in your browser, although some areas of our websites may not function properly if you do, including: Hershey's Gifts checkout, auto login, and membership. __ We do not rent, sell, or share e-mail addresses with any other company or organization.

Finally, we never use or share the personally identifiable information provided to us on-line in ways unrelated to the ones described above without also providing you an opportunity to opt-out or otherwise prohibit such unrelated uses.

Our Commitment To Data Security

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect on-line.

A Word To Parents About Kids’ Privacy

Our Privacy Policy applies to children as well as adults. There are some extra precautions that we take, however, with respect to collecting information from children under 13.

  * ~~_We encourage parents to explore our web sites with their children._~~
  * All promotion entrants will be requested to provide their age. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13 on-line without first obtaining permission from the child’s parent or guardian. When a child under 13 years old attempts to register for a promotion or sweepstakes, we send their parent or guardian an e-mail to get their permission to collect the child’s personally identifiable information as part of their registration. If we do not receive permission within 14 days, we will delete the child’s request and they will not be able to complete their registration or enter any promotions online. Once a parent or guardian gives their permission for their child to register, the parent will be asked to complete the child's mailing information on behalf of the child.  When complete, the child will be able to enter future registration-based sweepstakes or contests without any further requests of consent to the parent; however the parent will be notified when the child enters a promotion.  Should the child's personally identifiable information require updating, the parent will be required to make any and all updates to their child's online registration information on behalf of the child. If a child under 13 is a winner, we will contact you and/or your child by e-mail for prize fulfillment purposes.
  * We do not require a child to provide more personally identifiable information than is reasonably necessary to participate in an activity. (You may wish to be aware that, according to the FTC, web site operators are not permitted to collect more information than is needed for a child to participate in an on-line activity.)
  * Our web sites do not offer activities that allow your child or Hershey to disclose your child’s personal information publicly (for example through chat rooms or message boards).
  * We do not share your child’s personally identifiable information with third parties.
  * If you would like to review personally identifiable information about your child that we have on file, or request that certain information be changed or deleted, please contact:

> > > The Hershey Company  
>  Consumer Relations  
>  100 Crystal A Drive  
>  Hershey, PA 17033
>>> 
>>> Phone Toll Free 1-800-468-1714, or
>>> 
>>>  _**Contact us Online:**_  
>     
>   

**NOTICE: Visitwww.ftc.gov/kidzprivacy for information from the Federal Trade Commission about protecting children's privacy on-line.**

How You Can Access Or Correct Your Information

If it has not already automatically been deleted as explained above, you may review your or your child’s personally identifiable information, have it deleted and withdraw permission for its continued use by Hershey by _**[ Contacting Us Online](http://www.hersheys.com/contactus/contact-us-date.asp)**_. To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections. _In addition to this, all sweepstakes and www.hersheyskitchens.com websites let you edit your information online within that website._

This Privacy Policy Is For Our On-line Consumers

This Privacy Policy is for our consumers who visit our internet sites. It does not apply to information which we may collect by means other than over the Internet and it does not apply to businesses which may use our site.

Links

Our policy is to link only to other sites which are appropriate for visitors to our web site. However, content on web sites can change quickly, so we cannot always guarantee the appropriateness of the content of sites we link to.  _When you leave our site for another website, you will go first to a bumper page informing you that you are leaving our website._

How To Contact Us

Should you have other questions or concerns about our privacy policy, please don't hesitate to _**[ Contact us Online](http://www.hersheys.com/contactus/contact-us-date.asp)**_. You may also write to us at Public Relations Department, The Hershey Company, PO Box 810, 100 Crystal A Drive, Hershey, PA 17033 or call us at 1-800-468-1714. 

_\- Your Friends at The Hershey Company_ Copyright © The Hershey Company

**Effective:** November 24, 2008
